GNANASEKARAN GAJENDIRAN

DEVOPS ENGINEER - STANDARD CHARTERED, CHENNAI in 🦃





SUMMARY:

Over 8+ years IT experience in DevOps and Software Engineer in mission critical environments across the Banking industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem-solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics. Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, and automation, continuous deployment (CICD) pipelines for real-time.

Able to communicate effectively at all levels and able to work on own initiative or within a larger group including during crisis situations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

DevOps Ansible, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx, Liquibase

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeats, Metricbeat

SYSDIG, ITRS, SITESCOPE, MONIT Monitoring/Log Shell Scripting, Groovy, Gradle, Python Programming

RDBMS Oracle, MySQL.

Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu. OS Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, SSO, SSL, AWS Certifications RHCE, Ansible, ElasticSearch

EXPERIENCE:

Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using Ansible through CICD pipeline. StandardChartered

Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic Stack. **Devops Engineer** Introduced Nginx as Gateway & Dockerized it with F5 as load Balancer. Chennai Architecting/Designing infrastructure interms of RDMS, F5, SSL and SSO. (Jul2014-Present)

Good knowledge in ConfigServer, effectively used combination of ConfigServer and Ansible.

Infosys Private Ltd Responsible for High availability of Non-Production Environments.

Written Monitoring Scripts and Configured in SiteScope to alert services/MQ status. **Technology Analyst**

Troubleshooting on Network, SAN, DNS, LDAP, DB and OS Levels. Chennai

Developed Java based Tool to fetch application properties from several servers. (Mar2013-Jun2014)

Administering SiteScope and BladeLogic.

Implemented Single Click Deployment by using ControlTier. **HCL Technologies**

Automated ControlTier Tool Installation, Configuration and Jobs Creations. Software Engineer

Conducting knowledge transitions cross Support and Dev Teams. Chennai

Implemented ACLS with SUDOERS. (Dec2009-Feb2013)

Worked in Production Support, Automated Batch Process and Monitoring.

EDUCATION:

BE **Anna University**

Jun 2005 - Jun 2009 **Electronics and Communications Engineering**

High School Tamil Nadu, State Board

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry and Biology Jul2002 - May2005

MORE ABOUT ME:

Awards & Honours Promoted as Devops Engineer from StandardChartered Bank

Rewarded Best Performer Award (INSTA Award) and Buddy Award from Infosys

Honoured Best Performer Award (Live Wire Award) two times from HCL.

INTERESTS AWS, Kubernetes, Sysdig and Prometheus

Python, Gradle and Groovy

DEVOPS, Sleeping, Computer Programming, Surfing Internet **HOBBIES**

DOB 21-04-1987